Whenever we do a launch, part of the big
bit is okay, how does this translate
into our meta ads, into our Tik Tok ads.
And so we have a 11 laps app which has
all the best creative models, whether
it's speech, sound effects, music. And
as part of that, we release, for
example, the image and video feature
within it. As part of that, you then go,
okay, what are the ads that we should
do? What are the different hooks? And as
you're thinking and iterating on that
core messaging for the expost, you're
also thinking and iterating for the
different ad copy. Hello, I'm your host
David Bernard. Today's conversation is
shorter than usual and will be featured
in Revenue Cat's state of subscription
apps report. Each episode in this series
will explore one crucial topic and share
actionable insights from top
subscription app operators. With me
today, Luke Harris, who leads the growth
team at 11 Labs. On the podcast, I talk
with Luke about how 11 Labs turns every
new feature launch into a growth engine,
how they're deploying over a hundred
million dollars in paid ads, and why
directing AI agents is quickly becoming
a core skill for marketers and solo
founders. Hey Luke, thanks so much for
joining me on the podcast today. Excited
to be here.
>> I want to kick things off with how you
think about growth. You're at 11 Labs.
You guys are launching tons of cool
stuff, working on amazing products, but
you've also like been in the industry a
while and have been doing this for a
long time, working on growth. So, how do
you think at a high level about growth?
Yeah, with growth, we think about
building growth engines. And what a
growth engine for us is, it's a system
which we track and we optimize and we
set ambitious goals and we repeatedly
take this engineering approach to
marketing where we we try and level up
every time we do it. And so one specific
way we do this is through big launches.
And something which is very unique about
AI is that when you get a new model that
unlocks a new capability which gives you
a new viral moment. And so the heartbeat
of the growth team is working handinhand
with our incredible product and research
team such that when they're launching
new features, new models, new
capabilities, we put it through this
growth system and that normally
translates into what's hopefully a
really viral moment. So for example, we
have the world's best speechtoext model.
And so when we release Scribe V2, it's
like, okay, let's do an incredible video
and tweet thread to really show the
world how to do that and top all the
benchmarks, but then that also
translates behind the scenes into a
world-class landing page, sort of time
to update all your different meta, your
LinkedIn ads, your Google ads. So yeah,
the launches are really the heartbeat
for us. Yeah, I think this is really
overlooked in the broader industry. And
when you're working on a feature,
ideally you're working on something that
people are going to care about and that
that wouldn't be just your users. Like
it's a great opportunity to like expand
that messaging beyond just like putting
it in the app and putting an inapp
banner. Although some people don't even
do that. You know, a lot of apps don't
even have a like on launch open what's
new and hey check out this new feature
or a tool tip or you know those kind of
things to even hint at existing users
that this new capability is there much
less using that all that engineering
effort and and the creativity that goes
into this new feature as a moment to get
more attention. And you know, of course,
people are going to be listening like,
"Oh, well, look, earned media is so hard
to get these days." And it is, and 11
Labs has an easier time than a lot will
have getting that earned media, but you
don't know until you try. And I think
more apps should be trying. And then how
do you think about taking those launch
moments and using the ideas, the new
features, and things like that in your
paid assets as well? Because it's not
just about getting earned media. It's
about using these new features and that
creativity to to get attention even if
it's paid attention.
>> Yeah, 100%. So, whenever we do a launch,
part of the big bit is okay, how does
this translate into our meta ads, into
our Tik Tok ads and so we have a 11 laps
app which has all the best creative
models whether it's speech, sound
effects, music and as part of that we
release for example the image and video
feature within it. As part of that, you
then go, okay, what are the ads that we
should do? What are the different hooks?
And as you're thinking and iterating on
that core messaging for the expost,
you're also thinking and iterating for
the different ad copy. And one of the
new things we've actually just built,
which has been really cool, is we built
a custom GPT where we've analyzed what's
all the top performing meta and Google
copy and what's all our bottom
performing meta and Google copy. So we
normally take what's our like brand X
post and then we pass it through this
custom GPT which will then iterate on it
into like the high performing um meta
and Google copy. And then another big
bit which I'd be happy to dive into is
also we want to create lots of different
variants of images of videos of statics
in order to see what will drive
conversion.
>> Yeah I I did want to dive more
specifically into video. I mean, you
know, between reals and Tik Tok and I
mean, even a good expost with a video is
going to generally perform better than
just like a thread without any kind of
example. How do you think about in
generating these assets? When to use AI
creative, when to lean into UGC, and
when to just team create assets? On your
blog post, you talk about like put the
founder in front of a camera in Loom uh
showing off the product. People don't
often do those kind of things, but if
again if you're building something worth
attention, you can probably do a little
video like that. So, how do you how do
you think about balancing all of this?
Yeah, 100%. So, I think this will change
a lot in the next year or two, but now
in Feb 2026, what we found best is
normally actually you start with
agencies. So we started with agencies.
You're testing lots of different
formats. You work out what fits, but
then you want to bring it inhouse like
really optimize the quality but also
scaling up the quantity. And so we have
two people which have the job title AI
creative producers. And their task is
every day they're just obsessed. They're
using tools like motion. They're
obsessed with okay, what's the data of
what's working so far? What are other
companies in the space doing? and then
they're coming up with new creative
ideas and then rapidly iterating and
testing it. At the moment, what we found
works really well for our core app, so
our web app is they create with After
Effects really great motion design. So
that's their background. They are motion
designers, but then they layer in with
like text to speech voiceovers using
Lean Labs with the music and that
enables you to do like rapid testing
because you can test different hooks
with motion design. You can test
different voiceovers, different music.
So you get nice love variance, but you
also are able to keep the quality bar
really high. And uh other things we use
to boost production is lots of the AI
generated images we're also
incorporating into the motion design.
Are you still using UGC though? And like
how how do you think about UGC in this
mix of AI generated creative or AI
assisted creative plus you know the
in-house assets and you have motion
designers on staff like you've got a lot
going on. Are you also working with UGC?
>> Yeah, we do three main types of video
production inhouse. So the first one is
the motion design and that's still the
bulk of our ads and works like really
well. you can get like the quick hooks
and variants to really see like what
messaging resonates and particularly
with this like AI abstract UI based
flows. They're like great ways to show
it. The other team we have is a motion
design team but focused on all brand
videos and launches. And so they spend
like longer amount of time, fewer
variants. And then we also have a
in-house creator called Alec who has a
YouTube channel who just shows like how
do you get the very best out of these
tools and it's more like person in front
of the camera. I think there's
definitely a world where we can like try
supercharging that in future for the
educational side using the avatars, but
for now we really care about like
quality as well as quantity and like
actually a person in a studio making
really fantastic educational videos is a
great way to do that.
>> Yeah. You you shared with me before the
podcast that you're on track to spend
over $100 million in paid ads by the end
of the year. How do you think about
where to deploy that money with this
fire hose of creative? Because you know
one approach and what a lot of people
are doing is like okay AI is now helping
us create so much more creative let's
just throw money behind it and just see
what sticks is that what you're doing
with 100 million or or how how are you
approaching that?
>> Not quite. No. So the the way we view
about money and spending channels is we
actually view yes we have the top down
view but we're mainly thinking bottoms
up and so we treat each channel as its
own growth engine and actually our
biggest one still is Google and Google
search and so what we're doing is like
that we're obsessed of okay how do we
make really great ad copy how do we
localize it to all the geos how do we
have really high converting landing
pages and then it's like okay week over
week how do you scale scale it 10% 20%.
For Neta, it's a similar one where yes,
you want great amount of creative, but
you also want really high quality. And
then when I think about scaling creative
in order to get unlocked, what you
actually want to do is more
segmentation. So you're maybe using AI
to help. Before maybe if you just had a
general like here's how to make images
and videos with AI, but now you can go
that one level deeper like here's how
podcasters or here's how people making
apps can can create with image and video
and you can use like AI to do that like
personalization segmentation. The other
really big unlock for us has been the
localization side and that's where we've
really lent into AI. As a side note, we
initially went down the route of like
you pay an expensive SAS app for
localization, you pay for an agency to
then who have people to localize it. But
I kept on having our team just sending
screenshots of chat GPT being like, oh,
we should use this phrasing instead.
It's way better. And I was like, well,
if the LLMs are way better at
translation than these agencies and
expensive tooling. So, we actually
ripped out all the localization
infrastructure. We built our own GitHub
action and there's like a thin library
which just extracts the strings or wraps
all the strings and then each time we
make a PR to our repo it just sends it
with like a prompt per language about
the localization guide and that means
we're able to localize like way cheaper
and much faster. And then once we've
also localized the apps you're then able
to localize all the ads. There's stuff
like our dubbing model or again just
like passing the copy with good prompts
gets fantastic results. You know, we
think bottoms up. What's that next
bottleneck for us to like scale another
20% week on week, month on month and
then you start going through, okay,
first of all, it's like funnel
optimization. Then it's probably
starting to think about stuff like
localization and so forth. And how do
you think about measurement? And are you
mixing in brand and other things that
are harder to measure? I mean, with $100
million to spend, there's a lot more
room to experiment and potentially, you
know, put money into things that will
pay off more in the long run, but are
you looking at dollar for-doll ROI? Are
you looking that for some channels but
not others? How do you think about
measurement and effectively spending
that? Yeah. So, 11 Labs, we have
different bits of the business. We have
mobile, self-serve, web, and enterprise.
And each one of those we think about
brand and performance a bit differently
where the bulk of spend so far which is
still like self-s served web which has
nice parallels to mobile. The way we
think about it is like direct channel
ROI and you can be more direct response
when you're dealing with consumers or
proumers. And so there you're able to do
meta has lots of great tools. They tell
you about what the different conversions
and so forth are. But the important
thing to do is to run the lift studies
within the platform which actually doing
AB tests with hold out groups to tell
you because for a brand like 11 ads
where lots of people already know you'll
often end up with lots of people would
have converted anyway and particularly
as you start doing stuff like
retargeting ads. So that's able to give
you yes you were saying that 500 people
converted actually there was only an
incremental 200 because 300 people
converted anyway and then our system so
far is we pull all that data from the
platforms we then add incrementality
adjustments which we then update every
quarter and then that's how we use to to
allocate our budget.
>> Yeah. Fascinating. You're doing it at a
scale not a lot of companies are these
days in this space. The thing I wanted
to wrap up on and we kind of already
touched on it, but are we headed to a
future where marketers are more like AI
creative directors and and how do you
see this going moving forward with
leveraging AI in marketing? We actually
did this exercise internally around like
what does the future of marketing look
like and our sense is probably each
product will have a growth person who
has like really great taste and really
great ideas and then you work with the
engineering team and you go okay I'm
going to launch a product. So say we're
launching image and video creation in
our app. You then chat with an agent and
you're like hey we're launching this
product. It then like literally checks
through your codebase. It checks through
online like competitive landscape. It
reads through all your internal docs and
knowledge base and your personas. Helps
you craft like the core of the
messaging. Then it goes one step further
of like okay let me help storyboard out
what does this launch video look like
and how does that actually like
translate then when you put proper like
AI generated motion design as the models
get better. Maybe you're incorporating
some avatars to show like how do you
actually use the product and then that
launch point goes to like performance
marketing and performance marketing
creative. And the ideal is probably you
wake up every single day and you have 10
to 20 high performing ads where you can
like you set that brand direction.
You're that creative director of where
we're going and apply your taste. But
then you're like, "Yes, I like these.
No, I don't like these or these need to
be tweaked." you're chatting with it
maybe with voice and then it goes and
takes that one concept and adapts it for
the different screens whether it's
horizontal vertical it then localizes it
into the 70 plus languages so this is
yeah ideally what we're going to build
end to end with 11 creative good amount
of work to do I don't think anyone's
there yet I think people are saying
they're there we'll be there close
within the next couple of months but
yeah should be a lot of fun
>> yeah it's going to be a fascinating
couple of years I mean it already has
been the past couple years as we've
integrated more and more and it does
just feel like each person is able to do
more and more with the aid of AI and
that's just going to continue
accelerating. So I love that idea of
like one person in that kind of like
growth product position managing a bunch
of agents who help build those things
out I think is the way a lot of this is
going to go. I like that 100%. The other
bit which could be pretty cool is I
imagine lots of your audience are also
like the solo builders. The ideal is
maybe even you just have like connect
something to your GitHub. Every new PR
is just like monitoring what you're
shipping and then you just go I have an
idea. It builds the feature. It then
takes the feature and runs it through
the whole launch process and uh yeah,
spinning up your ads. So potentially the
first billion dollar startup could be
built like that.
>> Yeah. Well, this is so much fun chatting
through this. It's going to be
fascinating to see how things go the
next few years. And 11 Labs is right at
the center of it building a lot of this.
So, as we wrap up, anything else you
wanted to share? Uh, job you wanted to
hire out? I know y'all are working on
some stuff with a product called Flows
that'll come out later this year.
>> Yeah, I think main we're hiring lots of
mobile engineers, which I know you have
lots of fantastic, fantastic audience.
If you want to try it out, you can just
sign up, use the 11 creative product or
download any of our mobile apps and uh
hopefully you'll find it useful for your
own own growth and performance marketing
and excited to keep working with you
all.
>> Awesome. Thanks so much. Cool.
>> Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute, please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.
[music]